一位哲人曾經問：
Aphilosopher once asked,
「我們之所以是人類，是因為我們可以仰望繁星」
"Are we human because we gaze at the stars,
「還是因為我們是人類，所以才仰望星空呢？」
"or do we gaze at them because we are human?"
毫無意義，真的
Pointless, really-
星星們也會注視著我們麼？
Do the stars gaze back?
現在，便成了個問題
Now, that's a question-
但我好像說得早了點
But I'm getting ahead of myself-
我們的故事真正從這裡開始
Our story really begins here,
150年前的皇家科學院
1 50 years ago at the Royal Academy of Science
英國，倫敦
in London, England,
一封信被寄到了那，信中問了個奇怪的問題
where a letter arrived, containing a very strange inquiry-
提問的是個來自鄉下的男孩
It had come from a country boy
讀信的那位學者覺得
and the scientist who read it thought it might be a practical joke of some kind-
這可能是個男孩小小的惡作劇
但他還是按時寫了回信
But he duly wrote a reply
禮貌地表明…那個懷疑只是男孩胡亂的猜測
politely explaining that the query was nonsense-
信被郵到了男孩那兒，一個叫牆的村子
And posted it to the boy who lived in a village called Wall,
男孩說，村子之所以叫這個名字
so named, the boy had said, for the wall that ran alongside it-
是因為在村子的旁邊有一堵牆
當地流傳著一個傳說
A wall that, according to local folklore, hid an extraordinary secret-
這堵牆隱藏著一個特別的秘密
我的責任就是，守衛這個通向另一個世界的入口
I'm charged with guarding the portal to another world.
而你居然告訴我，你要讓我允許你從這通過？
And you're asking me to just Iet you through?
是啊，說實話，那就是個曠野
Yes. Because, Iet's be honest, it's a field.
看，你看見另一個世界了麼？
Look, do you see another world out there?
沒，你看到的是曠野
No. You see a field. Do you see anything nonhuman?
你看到任何非人類的東西了麼？
不，知道為什麼麼？因為那只是個曠野！
No. And you know why? Because it's a field!
幾百年來，這牆就一直在這
Hundreds of years, this wall's been here.
幾百年來，這條溝壑24小時有人看守
Hundreds of years, this gap's been under 24-hour guard.
好吧…　　再敢多說一句
-Well... -One more word,
我就把你拿到鄉村委員會去
and I'll have you up in front of the village council!
看來我們沒什麼好商量的了　　　是的
-Well, that sounds rather final. -Yeah.
我想我最好還是回家去吧
-Better just go home, then, I suppose. -Right, then. Night, Dunstan.
這就對了，那麼晚安，鄧斯坦
替我向你爸爸問好
Give my best to your father.
站住！
Stop!
我可不喜歡和磨蹭的人做生意
I don't deal with time-wasters.
滾過來看攤
Get over here and tend this stall.
我要去酒吧來上一杯
I'm off to The SIaughtered Prince for a pint.
看到喜歡的東西了麼？
See anything you like?
當然
Definitely.
我是說…我的意思是這些，我喜歡這些藍色的
I mean, what I meant was these ones, the blue ones.
多少錢？
How much are they?
我要你頭髮的顏色
They might be the color of your hair.
或是，你三歲前的全部記憶
Or they might be all of your memories before you were three.
如果你喜歡，我現在就可以結帳
I can check if you like.
總之，你不該買野風信子，買這個作為代替吧
Anyway, you shouldn't buy the bluebells. Buy this one instead.
雪蓮花
Snowdrop.
它能給你帶來幸運
It'll bring you Iuck.
但是這個我要付出什麼呢？
But what does that cost?
一個吻
This one costs a kiss.
她走了麼？
Is she gone?
跟我來
Follow me.
我是個公主…被陷害，成了女巫的奴隸
I'm a princess, tricked into being a witch's slave.
你會救我麼？
Will you liberate me?
這是條施了魔法的鏈子，只有她死了我才能自由
It's an enchanted chain. I'll only be free when she dies.
對不起
Sorry.
如果我救不了你，你又為什麼讓我進去呢？
Well, if I can't liberate you, what do you want of me?
所以，這位學者錯了
So, the scientist was wrong-
這堵牆成功地完成了它的使命
The wall had successfully done its job
這使命就是保衛魔法王國風暴要塞不被發現
of hiding the magical kingdom of Stormhold-
那晚，年輕人回到了在英國的家
The young man returned that night to his home in England,
希望這次冒險會很快被遺忘
hoping that his adventure would soon be forgotten-
但是九個月之後
But nine months later, he received an unexpected souvenir-
他收到了一份意想不到的紀念品
這個是給你的，被留在牆邊
This was Ieft at the wall for you. It says here his name is Tristan.
上面說，他的名字叫特裡斯頓
魔　幻　星　塵
特裡斯頓？別忘了帶上花
Tristan? Don't forget the flowers.
是的，我帶著呢，謝謝，爸爸
Yes. I've got them. Thank you, Father.
十八年過去了，這個嬰兒特裡斯頓長大了
Eighteen years passed, and the baby Tristan grew up
對自己非比尋常的身世一無所知
knowing nothing of his unconventional heritage-
不過，不用去多想…
But never mind how the infant became a boy-
一個嬰兒是怎樣長成一個男孩的
這個故事是關於特裡斯頓·索朗…
This is the story of how Tristan Thorn becomes a man,
是怎樣變成一個男人的
這可要經歷更大的挑戰
a much greater challenge altogether-
為了達到這個目標
For to achieve it,
他必須贏得真愛的芳心
he must win the heart of his one true love-
是他！　　是他！
-It's him! -It's him!
漢弗萊？
Humphrey?
不，我是特裡斯頓　　　哦…
-No, it's Tristan. -Oh.
我把什麼落在商店裡了麼？
Did I Ieave something at the shop?
沒，我只是想，我能帶這個…
No. I just thought I could bring...
特裡斯頓·索朗
Tristan Thorn,
白天在商店打雜，晚上跑來偷看女人
shop boy by day, peeping Tom by night.
你到底有完沒完了？
Is there no end to your charms?
漢弗萊，沒必要那樣
Humphrey, there's no need to be like that.
對這個窮小子好一點
Be nice to the poor boy.
這些是給維多利亞的麼？
Were those for Victoria?
特裡斯頓，在學校，你的劍術總是那麼沒用
You were always useless at fencing in school, Tristan.
事實上，我實在是想不出你到底擅長什麼
In fact, I'm having trouble remembering if there was anything you were good at.
漢弗萊，夠了
Humphrey, that's enough.
你還好麼？
Are you all right?
是，是的，我很好
Yeah. Yeah, fine.
來點早餐？　　不，我要遲到了
-Want some breakfast? -No, I'm really Iate for work.
昨晚還好麼？　　是的，很好，怎麼了？
-Are you all right? -Yeah. Fine. Why?
哦，我也說不好，昨晚發展的怎樣？
Oh, I don't know. Last night, how'd it go?
哦，真的很好，真的，真的很好
Oh, really good. Really, really good.
你好，特裡斯頓
Hello, Tristan.
維多利亞　　　一磅糖，謝謝
-Victoria. -Pound of sugar, please.
好的
-Yes. -Let's see, a bag of flour, a dozen eggs.
讓我看看，我還要一袋麵粉，一打雞蛋
聽著，我為昨晚的事道歉，漢弗萊太粗魯了
Oh, Iook, I'm sorry about Iast night. Humphrey was really rude.
我還要一大袋土豆和一些巧克力，謝謝
I also need a sack of potatoes and some chocolate, please.
我今晚可以去看你麼？
May I perhaps see you tonight?
不，但你可以送我回家
No, but you may walk me home.
現在？
Now?
是的，是的，我能
Yes. Yes, I can.
爸，我丟了工作
Father, I Iost my job.
爸，我沒有…我的工作沒了，對不起
Father, I don't... I Iost my job. I'm sorry.
爸爸　　　你被開除了
-Father... -You Iost your job.
是的，我聽說了
Yes, so I heard.
爸爸，對不起，我…
Father, I'm sorry. I...
也許曼德先生說得對，我是在自欺欺人
Maybe Mr. Monday was right. Maybe I am deluding myself.
我配不上維多利亞
-I'm not good enough for Victoria. -He said that? That's poppycock.
他是這麼說的？真是一派胡言
你真想知道那晚怎麼樣了？
You really want to know how it went Iast night?
是的
Yeah.
不好
Not good.
算了，我在浪費時間
Come on. I'm wasting my time.
我不像漢弗萊
I'm not like Humphrey.
特裡斯頓，我想告訴你
Tristan, I can tell you that every man I ever envied when I was a boy
我崇拜的每個人，在我還是個孩子的時候
他們的生活都在平常不過了
has Ied an unremarkable life.
所以你現在不太招人喜歡
So you don't fit with the popular crowd. Now, I take that as a very good omen.
我把它看作是一個非常好的預兆
特裡斯頓，我說得很清楚了…
-Tristan, I clearly said... -I know. You told me not to come.
我知道，你告訴我不要來
我有些東西想給你，一個驚喜
I have something for you. A surprise.
不…
No...
你是知道的，我還有一星期才過生日呢
It's not my birthday for another week, you know.
我以前從沒喝過香檳　　　是啊，我也沒喝過
-I've never had champagne before. -Yeah, me, neither.
天啊！真好喝！
My God! This is delicious!
你怎麼…一個商店的人怎能付得起這個？
How did... Well, how does a shop boy afford all of this?
我不是商店裡的人
I'm not a shop boy.
天！我聽說了，對不起，你現在想怎麼辦？
God! I heard. I'm sorry. What are you going to do now?
不…我不是商店打雜的，我是在商店工作
No. I mean, I'm not a shop boy. I was just working in a shop.
而現在我不在了，我自由了，我可以過好日子
And now I'm not. Now I'm free to live my life as I wish.
這一定花掉了你全部積蓄
This must have been all your savings.
怎麼樣？我可以做得更好，真是太美了
So? I can make more. That's the beauty of it.
我從沒打算固守一隅，維多利亞
I never intended to stay in Wall, Victoria.
外面的世界很大，我要去冒險
There's a big world out there, I'm gonna make my fortune.
現在你聽起來像漢弗萊，他是個十足的旅者
Now you sound just like Humphrey. He's quite a traveler.
你知道麼，他要一路走去伊普斯威奇
Do you know he's going all the way to ipswich just to buy me a ring?
就為了給我買一枚戒指
伊普斯威奇？
ipswich?
維多利亞，我說的是倫敦，巴黎或是…
Victoria, I'm talking about London or Paris or...
戒指？他為什麼…什麼戒指？
A ring? Why is he... What kind of a ring?
他打算在我的生日時向我求婚
The word is he's planning to propose to me on my birthday.
他打算…
He's going to...
你會說願意？
And you're gonna say yes.
他一路走去伊普斯威奇，我怎能說不呢？
I can't exactly say no after he's gone all the way to ipswich.
「一路走去伊普斯威奇」？
"All the way to ipswich"?
維多利亞，如果能牽著你的手走進教堂
Victoria, for your hand in marriage, I'd cross oceans or continents.
我願意翻越萬水千山
真的？　　是的
-Really? -Yes.
維多利亞，如果能牽著你的手走進教堂
Victoria, for your hand in marriage,
我願意去舊金山淘金
I would go to the gold fields of San Francisco
給你帶回成堆的金子
and bring you back your weight in gold.
我願意
I would.
我願意去非洲，給你帶回拳頭大的鑽石
I'd go to Africa and bring you back a diamond as big as your fist.
或者，我願意去北極，殺一隻北極熊
Or I'd go to the Arctic and I'd slaughter a polar bear
把它的頭帶給你
and bring you back its head.
一隻北極熊的頭？
A polar bear's head?
你真好玩，特裡斯頓
You're funny, Tristan.
像你…我這樣的人，我們只是…
People like you and people like me, we're just not...
我要走了，真的有點晚了
I should be going. It's really Iate.
不，等等，至少讓我們把香檳喝完
Well, hold on, then. Let's at Ieast finish the champagne.
好吧
Okay.
要是特裡斯頓知道，當時群星是怎樣看著地球
Had Tristan known then how the stars watched Earth,
他一定會擔心
he'd have shuddered at the very thought
會被這些特別的觀眾羞辱
of an audience to his humiliation-
但是，幸運的是
But, fortunately for him,
那時，天空中幾乎所有的星星
nearly every star in the sky was at that moment
都在注視著東方的大地，牆另一邊的世界
Iooking in earnest at the land on the other side of the wall,
風暴要塞的國王正躺在臨終的床上
where the King of all Stormhold lay on his deathbed,
也許是個巧合，因為國王的最後這一行為
which was a coincidence because it was the King's final act
將永遠地改變特裡斯頓一生的命運
that would change the course of Tristan's destiny forever-
塞肯多斯在哪？
Where is Secundus?
他在回來的路上，父親
He's on his way, Father.
那麼我們只好等了
Then we shall wait.
對不起，我來晚了，父親
Sorry I'm Iate, Father. I came as swiftly as I was able.
我已經以最快的速度趕回來了
塞普蒂默斯
Septimus.
普裡默斯
Primus.
特修斯
Tertius.
那麼，關於繼承權的問題
So, to the matter of succession.
我的七個兒子，尚有四個站在這裡
Of my seven sons, there are four of you today still standing.
這可以說是破了先例了，我有十二個兄弟
This is quite a break with tradition. I had 12 brothers.
為了王位，您把他們都殺了
And you killed them all for your throne
就連您的父親…國王…也自嘆不如
before your father, the King, even felt poorly.
我們都知道，父親，您很強壯，有膽識
We know, Father. You're strong and courageous.
奸詐，最重要的是，奸詐
And cunning. Most importantly, cunning.
塞肯多斯　　　是的，父親
-Secundus. -Yes, Father?
看窗外，告訴我，你看到了什麼？
Look through the window. Tell me what you see.
我看到了王國，父親
I see the kingdom, Father.
整個風暴要塞
The whole of Stormhold.
還有呢？　　我的王國？
-And? -My kingdom?
也許，向上看
Maybe. Look up.
塞肯多斯　　　塞克多斯，闊多斯，昆多斯
-Secundus. -Sextus. Quartus. Quintus.
你還活著，你還…
You're alive. You're...
像這樣被困在這，直到新國王加冕
Stuck like this till the new king is crowned.
我離王位就差一步了
I was that close.
算了吧，至少你看起來還像個人樣
Well, at Ieast you haven't Iost your Iooks.
可別這麼說，你還在為被謀殺的事耿耿於懷吧
Oh, please. You're not annoyed about that whole murder thing, are you?
…那已經是十年前的事了　　　是啊
-I mean, that was 10 years ago. -Yeah.
殺了我給你增色不少吧…塞肯多斯？
Great deal of good it did you, didn't it, killing me, Secundus?
因為現在，當然，你就是風暴要塞的國王了
Because now, of course, now you are King of all Stormhold.
抱歉，等一下，不，你不是，你已經死了
Oh, sorry. Wait. No, you're not. You're dead.
烏拉？烏拉？
Una? Una?
不，父親，是我，你的兒子
No, Father, it's me, your son.
特修斯
Tertius.
你的姐姐烏拉在哪？
Where is your sister, Una?
對不起，父親，已經有好幾年沒人看到烏拉了
Sorry, Father. Nobody has seen Una for years now.
塞普蒂默斯？　　什麼？
-Septimus? -What?
傳統規定王位必須傳給男性繼承人
Tradition dictates the throne must pass to a male heir.
正是如此，父親
Exactly, Father.
幾個白癡都還活著，我也沒理由殺害我姐姐
So why would I kill my sister when these cretins are still alive?
確實是這樣
Indeed.
因此，我們得用一個非常規的方法
Therefore, we shall resolve the situation in a non-traditional manner.
來解決現在這個局面
只有擁有皇室血統的人，才能重鑄這塊紅寶石
Only he of royal blood can restore the ruby.
如果你們中的一個辦到了
And the one of you that does so shall be the new King of Stormhold.
那他就是風暴要塞的新國王
哦，特裡斯頓！一顆流星！
Oh, Tristan! A shooting star!
真美
Beautiful.
比伊普斯威奇帶回來的華麗戒指還美麼？
More beautiful than a fancy ring from ipswich?
維多利亞，如果可以牽你的手走進教堂
Victoria, for your hand in marriage,
我願意跨過牆，把那顆墜落的星帶給你
I'd cross the wall and I'd bring you back that fallen star.
你不能翻過牆去
You can't cross the wall.
每人能翻過這堵牆，你剛才是傻了吧
Nobody crosses the wall. Now you're just being silly.
我沒有傻，我願意那麼做
I'm not being silly. I'd do it.
為了你，我願意做任何事
For you, I'd do anything.
我自己的星星
My very own star.
看來我們倆有個一個約定
It seems we have ourselves an agreement.
你只有一星期時間，否則我就要嫁給漢弗萊
You have exactly one week or I'm marrying Humphrey.
莫拉！恩普拉！快起來！現在！
Mormo! Empusa! Wake up. Now!
怎麼了？　　一顆星墜落了
-What is it? -A star has fallen.
我的巴比倫蠟燭呢？
Where are the Babylon candles?
你在二百年前把最後一根用光了，你不記得了？
You used the Iast one, Lamia, 200 years ago. Do you not recall?
我們也許可以再找一個
Perhaps we can obtain another.
難道你的腦子和你的臉一樣愚蠢麼，恩普拉？
Has your mind become as decrepit as your face, Empusa?
別信口開河
You speak as if such things are freely available.
我知道，姐姐，我只是想…
I know, sister, I merely thought...
你讓我們去找巴比倫蠟燭
You'd have us hunting for a Babylon candle
而此時，其他女巫就可能找到了我們的星星
while some other witch finds our star.
笨蛋，沒時間浪費了
Fool. There's no time to waste.
如果我們要用走的，那我們要…
If we must retrieve it on foot, then we shall.
莫拉，我要知道方位
Mormo, we need information.
如果預言是正確的
If these divinations are correct, the fallen star lies 1 00 miles away.
這顆星墜落在一百公里的地方
我們為這個已經等了幾個世紀了
Four centuries we've waited for this. What hardship a few more days?
再多等幾天又有什麼難的呢？
我們中誰去把它找回來呢？
Which of us shall go, then, to seek it and bring it back?
我拿的是腎　　　我的是肝臟
-I've his kidney. -I've his liver.
我拿的是心臟
And I've his heart.
我需要，上一顆星星留下的東西
You'll be needing what's Ieft of the Iast star.
已沒剩多少了　　　很快，我們又會有許多
-There's not much Ieft. -Soon, there'll be plenty for us all.
鄧斯坦·索朗，休想再來一次
-Dunstan Thorn. Not again. -It's Tristan, actually.
事實上，我是特裡斯頓
噢，你和你父親長得可真像
Oh. You do Iook a bit like your father.
我想你也是打算要跨越這堵牆，是麼？
And I suppose you intend to cross the wall as well, do you?
好吧，還是忘了這事，回家去吧
Well, you can forget it. Go home.
也跨越這堵牆，那是誰？
Cross the wall as well as who?
沒誰，沒有人
No one. Nobody.
沒有人跨過牆去，你知道的！
Nobody crosses the wall. You know that!
每個人都知道！
Everybody knows that!
是啊…不不，我知道，我瞭解，沒有人
Yeah... No, no, I know. I understand. Nobody.
那麼，我最好還是回老家嘍
Well, I better just head for the old homestead, then.
是的
Yeah.
這樣才對，那麼晚安，特裡斯頓　　　晚安
-Right, then. Night, Tristan. -Good night.
給你爸爸帶好
Give my best to your father.
還是回去吧
Off you go.
我聽見你進屋的聲音了
I thought I heard you come in. Hey, what happened? Are you hurt?
嘿，怎麼了？你挨打了？
不，我沒事
No, I'm fine.
又是漢弗萊干的？　　不
-That Humphrey again? -No.
事實上，是那個看守，那個看牆的人
Actually, it was the guard. The guard at the wall.
特裡斯頓，他已經有97歲了
Tristan, he's 97 years old.
是啊，所以他用了足夠的時間來練習？
Well, that's given him plenty of time to practice, then, hasn't it?
我能問你，為什麼你要跨過那堵牆呢？
Why, may I ask, were you trying to cross the wall?
這也是我想問的事
I might ask you the same thing.
我有一個媽媽
I have a mother.
我是說我有個媽媽，她可能還活著
I mean, I have a mother. She could still be alive.
哦，我也希望如此，我當然也想這樣
Oh, I hope so. I certainly like to think so.
你砍下的鏈子
The chain you cut.
和你說的一樣
Just like you said.
還有…
And...
玻璃花，她賣給你的花
And the glass flower. The flower she sold to you.
她說它能帶給我幸運
She told me it would bring me Iuck.
謝謝
Thank you.
這個也是在籃子裡帶的，我從沒打開過
This was also in the basket. I've never opened it.
是寫給你的
It's addressed to you.
哦
Yep.
「我親愛的特裡斯頓，請你理解
"My dearest Tristan, please know that I only ever wanted the best for you."
我只想把最好的給你」
若我的主人允許，我願與你形影不離
Had my mistress allowed it, I would have kept you in a heartbeat-
我最大的願望，就是有一天，能夠見到你
My dearest wish is that we will meet someday-
最快的旅行的方法就是利用蠟燭的光
The fastest way to travel is by candlelight-
用它，想著我，只想著我
To use it, think of me and only me-
我會每一天都像你，永遠
I will think of you every day, for always-
「你的母親」
"Your mother."
你有…你有火麼？
Well, do you... Do you have a light?
媽媽？
Mother?
哦…媽媽，我…對不起，你還好麼？
Oh! Oh, Mother, I'm so... I'm so sorry. Are you all right?
不，我不是…你媽媽，從我身上下去！
No, I'm not. And I'm not your mother, so get off me!
你…你不是我媽媽？
You're... You're not my mother?
你覺得我看起來像你媽媽麼？
Do I Iook like I'm your mother?
不
No.
對不起
Sorry.
那麼，你還好麼？需要幫忙麼？
Well, are you all right? Do you want some help?
你唯一能幫我的就是離我遠點
You can help by Ieaving me alone!
好吧
All right.
哦，天啊！「點蠟燭，想我」
Oh, my God. "Light the candle and think of me."
我剛剛，我是在想我的…
I was. I was thinking of my...
只是，維多利亞和那顆星忽然閃過腦子
But then Victoria and the star just popped into...
哦，打擾一下，女士，對不起
Oh, excuse me, madam. Sorry.
這可能有點奇怪，但你有沒有看到一顆星掉下來？
This may seem strange, but have you seen a fallen star anywhere?
你真好笑　　　不，真的，我們現在在坑裡
-You're funny. -No, really, we're in a crater.
這一定是它掉下來的地方
This must be where it fell.
是啊，這是它掉下來的地方
Yeah, this is where it fell.
就這樣，還是你想知道得具體點
It is. Or if you want to be really specific,
就在上面，奇怪的是，一條帶血的項鏈
up there is where this weird, bloody necklace
不知道從哪飛出來，從天空砸了下來
came out of nowhere and knocked it out of the heavens
它只是在想自己的事情
when it was minding its own business.
而這，就是它掉下來的地方
And over there is where it Ianded.
就在那，他被一個會飛的魔法白癡撞倒了！
And right here, this is where it got hit by a magical flying moron!
你就是那顆星！你是那顆星？真的？
You're the star! You're the star? Really?
哦，哇，對不起，我不知道你…
Oh, wow. I'm sorry. I had no idea you'd be a...
首先請允許我說聲對不起
May I just say in advance that I am sorry?
為什麼對不起？　　就為這個
-Sorry for what? -For this.
我若沒想錯，這你就得和我一起走了
Now, if I am not mistaken, this means you have to come with me.
聽著，你要成為我的真愛，維多利亞的壽禮
See, you're going to be a birthday gift for Victoria, my true Iove.
但是，當然！
But of course!
綁架一個受傷的女人做生日禮物，太浪漫了！
Nothing says romance like the gift of a kidnapped, injured woman!
我哪都不和你去
I'm not going anywhere with you.
快點，你該在路上了，普裡默斯
Hurry. You should be on your way now, Primus.
你得在你兄弟之前找到那條紅寶石項鏈
You must find the royal necklace with the ruby before your brothers.
我真希望看到你能奪取王位
I should like to see you take the throne. The first benevolent king.
第一任仁慈的國王
我從沒懷疑過，如果你來統治…
I don't doubt Stormhold would be a better place under your rule.
風暴要塞會變得更好
真的？
Really?
那真是太好了
Well, that is fascinating.
你不這麼想，特修斯？　　我也是這樣想
-Don't you think, Tertius? -Yes, indeed.
塞普蒂默斯王子！ 特修斯…我…
Prince Septimus! Tertius. Well... Well. Well, well, I...
既然你們都來了，何不一起喝一杯呢？
Since you're all here, won't you join me in a toast?
真是個不錯的主意
What a very good idea.
為風暴要塞的新國王乾杯
To the new King of Stormhold,
不管你們兄弟中誰成為國王
whichever of you fine fellows it might be.
為風暴要塞的新國王乾杯
To the new King of Stormhold.
你！
You!
你真覺得你會成為國王？
You really thought that you were king?
你殺了主教？　　不，普裡默斯
-You killed the Bishop? -No, Primus.
我想你知道，是你拿錯了杯子才害了主教的
I think you'll find that you killed the Bishop by drinking out of the wrong cup.
聽著，在你和你的良知糾纏完後
Oh, Iook, when you finish wrestling with your conscience,
我可以建議你還是回到你的房間麼？
may I suggest you return to your chamber?
找石頭的事就交給我吧
Leave the quest for the stone to me.
我們這幾年怎麼這樣生活？
How have we lived this way all these years?
我不在時，希望你們能讓它適合…
In my absence, I expect you to make it fit for the queens we are.
像我們這樣的女王居住
當我帶回獎品，我們所有人就又會年輕了
When I return with our prize, all of us shall be young again.
別害怕，妹妹們
Never fear, my sisters.
我不會失敗的
I will not fail.
你都不睡覺的麼？
Don't you ever sleep?
晚上不
Not at night.
可能沒引起你的注意，天才
May have escaped your notice, genius,
但是當晚上到來時，對星星而言
but that's when stars have rather better things to do.
沒有比出來發光這樣的事更好的了
They're coming out, shining, that sort of thing.
是啊…不過你可能沒注意到你已不在天上了
Yeah, well, it may have escaped yours, but you're not in the sky anymore.
出去已經不在日程上了
Coming out is off the agenda.
發光嘛，暫停直到另行通知
Shining has been suspended until further notice.
哦，在白天睡覺的日子，沒…有…啦
Oh, and sleeping during the day is O-U-T.
除非你有什麼可以邊走邊睡的魔法
Unless you have some magical ability to sleep while you're walking.
你那魚木腦袋還沒搞清楚麼
Have you not got it into your thick head yet?
我哪也不去！
I'm not walking anywhere!
好吧
Fine.
在坑裡坐著吧，反正我也受夠你了
Sit in a crater. I've had enough of you anyway.
我本打算把你一帶給維多利亞，就送你回天上
I was gonna put you back in the sky once I'd brought you to my Victoria,
但顯然，你情願永遠坐在這…哪也不去
but clearly, you'd rather sit on your own in the middle of nowhere forever.
只是你要怎麼送我會天上呢？
And just how were you planning to get me back to the sky?
我知道最快的旅行的方法是通過蠟燭的光
I find the fastest way to travel is by candlelight.
你有巴比倫蠟燭？　　是，我有巴比零蠟燭
-You've got a Babylon candle. -Yeah, I have a bubbling candle.
是巴比倫蠟燭　　　我就是那麼說的啊
-A Babylon candle. -That's what I said.
你說的是「巴比零」
You said "Bubbling."
不管怎樣，我都會把剩下的給你
Anyway, I was going to give what's Ieft of it to you.
好吧，這個已經用得沒剩多少了
Well, that barely has one use Ieft.
那你該高興我現在不會用它…
So be grateful I'm not using it right now to get us both back to the wall.
讓我們倆馬上回到牆那去
除非你有帶自己回家更好的辦法
Unless you have a better way of getting yourself home.
好吧！
Fine!
扶我起來
Help me up.
好的，好的，我正在扶
All right. All right. I'm helping.
你得快點走
And you are gonna have to walk quicker than that.
否則，我一周內就趕不回維多利亞身邊
Otherwise, I'll never get you back to Victoria in a week.
欲速不達
Don't push your Iuck.
少於一弗羅林不賣，伯納德！聽明白了？
Don't take Iess than a florin for him, Bernard! You understand?
是，媽媽　　　別磨磨蹭蹭的！
-Yes, Mother. -No dilly-dallying!
也別想在酒館歇著，伯納德，否則有你好看！
And don't even think of stopping at the tavern, Bernard, or you'll be sorry!
一弗羅林買這隻羊，男孩
A florin for your goat, boy.
噢
Oh.
它有點小，拉不動你的車
He's a bit small to pull your cart.
說得很對
You're quite right.
這樣就好多了
That's much better.
伯納德！
Bernard!
快點
Get on!
你是誰？
Who goes there?
你要把我怎麼樣，我只是個窮賣花的…
What do you want with me, a poor old flower...
哦，快閉嘴，我知道你是做什麼的
Oh, do shut up. I know what you are
我發誓你和我是一道的
and I swear by the ordinances of the sisterhood to which we both belong
我是說今天你不會傷人
that I mean you no harm this day.
我只是想吃點東西
I wish to share your meal.
好吧，一個人總是要小心些才好
Well, one can never be too careful. Sit down. I'll get you a seat.
坐下吧，我給你拿個椅子
還要點別的麼？　　不
-Anything else? -Nope.
要那部分？
What's it to be?
頭還是尾巴？
Heads or tails?
頭
Heads.
那麼，陌生人
So, stranger,
這麼好的天，你趕著去哪？
where are you headed off to on this fine day?
我正在找一顆墜落的星星
I seek a fallen star.
她在離這不遠的地方掉下來了
She fell not far from here.
當我找到她，我要拿出我的刀
And when I find her, I shall take my great knife
趁她還活著，把她的心挖出來
and cut out her heart while she still lives.
讓我青春永駐
And the glory of our youth shall be restored.
墜落的星？
Fallen star?
對我這上了年紀的人，這可是最好的消息了
That's the best news I've had in ages.
我可以再年輕幾歲
I could do with Iosing a few years meself.
那你知道她的下落…
So whereabouts did you...
異形草！
Limbus grass!
你居然敢讓我吃異形草…來套我的話？
You dare to steal truth from my lips by feeding me limbus grass?
你知道你犯了一個多大的錯誤麼？
Do you have any idea what a big mistake you've made, Ditchwater Sal?
你怎麼知道我…
How do you know my...
你是誰？　　看仔細點
-Who are you? -Look again.
我不是要找您的星，我發誓，黑暗女王
I shall not seek the star, Your Dark Majesty. I swear.
這就是你的想法
Seek all you wish.
你不准看到星星的，摸到或是聞到它
You shall not see the star, touch it, smell or hear it.
即使她站在你眼前，你也感覺不到她的存在
You will not perceive her even if she stands before you.
祈禱你永遠不會再遇見我吧
Pray you never meet me again, Ditchwater Sal.
哦，好吧，我就直說了吧
Oh, right. So Iet me get this straight.
你以為你知道我們走的路沒錯，因為…
You think you know we're going the right way because...And I quote, "I just do."
我是這樣覺得，儘管我也不知為什麼
I do, though. I don't know why.
也許是我的對維多利亞的愛在指引我回家
Maybe it's my Iove for Victoria guiding me home.
拜託　　　亞尼，你是不是不想…
-PIease. -Yvonne, whether you like it or not...
亞伊尼！我的名字是亞伊尼，那麼…
Yvaine! My name is Yvaine, so...
我得和你說多少遍…
How many times do I have to...
你能…你能走慢點麼？
Would you... Would you please slow down?
是的，是的
Yes, yes.
聽著，我們…要向北走，對麼？
Look, we're... We're going north, all right?
牆在北邊
The wall's north.
如果你抬頭看天，即使白天，你也能看到…
And if you Iook up in the sky, even during the day, you can see the...
晚上的星星，很奇怪
The evening star. That's so weird.
真好笑，好笑，我都要累死了
That's funny. Hilarious. My sides are splitting.
不，我只是在…
No, I'm being...
等一下…那是你！真的？
Wait that... That was you! Really?
什麼…幹什麼…
What... What are...
你在做什麼？　　你看我像是在做什麼？
-What are you doing? -What does it Iook like I'm doing?
坐下，我累了　　　請別再這樣了
-Sitting down. I'm tired. -PIease don't do this again.
說好了的，在下個村子停下吃東西休息
We agreed we'd stop off at the next village to eat and rest.
拜託，特裡斯頓，現在是中午
Come on, Tristan. It's midday.
我從沒這麼晚還沒睡！
I never stay up this Iate! Just, please, Iet me sleep!
就一會，求你了，讓我睡一會！
好吧，那…你睡覺，我去找點吃的
Okay, you... Well, then I'll... You sleep. I'll go and get something to eat.
你這是做什麼？
What are you doing?
我看起來像是在做什麼？
What does it Iook like I'm doing? I'm making sure you don't run away.
當然是確保你不會逃走啦
殿下，這是你要的占卜者
Your Highness, the soothsayer, as you requested.
南面，你說的？
South, you said.
我們去了南面
South we went.
還是沒有石頭
Still no stone.
你現在又想讓我們去游泳麼？
Do you now propose we start swimming?
陛下，我只是向您傳達占卜石上告訴我的事
Sire, I've merely relayed to you what the runes have told me.
我幫不了什麼忙了
I can do no more.
好吧，那你和他們再商量一次
Well, consult them again.
等等
Wait.
在開始找石頭之前，我還有個問題
Before we seek the stone, I have another question.
我是第七個兒子麼？
Am I the seventh son?
是的
Yes.
另一個問題
Another question.
我最喜歡的顏色是藍色麼？
Is my favorite color blue?
是
Yes.
我有聽信過沒用的請求和辯解麼？
Has excessive begging or pleading ever persuaded me
尤其是對那些活得太久或是叛國者？
to spare the life of a traitor?
這個意味著什麼？
What does that mean?
意思是，不　　　很好
-That means no. -Good.
再扔一次，這一次，仍高點
Throw them again. This time, throw them high.
你是為我弟弟工作的麼？
Do you work for my brother?
那麼？我們繼續向西？
So, do we continue west?
特裡斯頓？
Tristan?
誰？
Who's there?
特裡斯頓，是你麼？
Tristan, is that you?
這一點也不好玩
It's not funny.
特裡斯頓？
Tristan?
到這邊來
Come on.
留心你用了多少魔法，姐姐
Be careful how much magic you use, sister.
已經開始顯現了
It's beginning to show.
只是一隻小羊和一小點迷幻術
One goat and a small enchantment. Hardly extravagant.
幾乎沒用過什麼奢侈的魔法
連用一下戒指也會損害它
Well, even using the ring will take its toll.
下次有急事時，再找我們兩個
Better you call on us only in dire need.
用占卜石自己確定星星的位置
And use your runes to Iocate the star yourself.
但現在，他們簡直是在胡說八道
But now they're just telling me gibberish.
你得待在那等，我的妹妹
It is because you must stay where you are, my sister.
她會走向你的
She is coming to you.
哦，要小心，拉米亞，要注意細節
Oh, be warned, Lamia. Delicacy is needed.
痛苦困擾著她，她幾乎不能發光了
Misery has drained her. She's barely shining.
設個陷阱，確保她在你挖出她的心之前…
Set a trap that ensures her heart is glowing before you cut it out.
還是生機勃勃的
亞伊尼！亞伊尼！
Yvaine! Yvaine!
哦，你這個傻瓜
Oh, you idiot.
你可以變成人了
You shall become human.
你叫比利，旅館的主人
You are Billy, the innkeeper. I am your wife, and you're our daughter.
我是你妻子，而你是我們的女兒
現在，以求準備就緒
Now, make everything ready. Our special guest will be here soon.
我們特殊的客人馬上就要來了
誰能保證他會信守關於蠟燭的諾言呢？
I mean, who's to say he'd have even kept his promise about the candle?
我不相信，他是在風暴要塞唯一一個
I just refuse to believe he's the only person in Stormhold
能幫我的人
who could've helped me.
翻來覆去地只說「維多利亞這個…那個」
Going on and on and on. Just "Victoria this" and "Victoria that."
特裡斯頓？
Tristan?
請保護我們的妹妹，特裡斯頓
Please protect our sister, Tristan-
亞伊尼正處在危險中
Yvaine is in grave danger-
獨角獸去幫她了
The unicorn came to help her-
但是現在他們正走向一個圈套
But now they're heading into a trap-
在風暴要塞，沒有星星是絕對安全的
No star is safe in Stormhold-
400年前，上個星星墜落了
The last to fall, 400 years ago,
她被女巫捕獲了
was captured by the same witches who seek Yvaine now-
現在尋找亞伊尼的，正是那群女巫
她們欺騙了她
They tricked her,
照顧她
cared for her,
知道她的心再次發光
and when her heart was once more aglow,
然後剖開她的胸膛，把心拿出來
they cut it from her chest
再吃了它
and ate it-
不能再浪費時間了
There's no time to waste-
馬車馬上就來了
A coach is coming-
不管用什麼方法，你一定要坐上去
By any means possible, you must get on it-
快！
Run-
哇！
Whoa!
如果要我送個男孩給他幹活
If Septimus insists on sending a boy to do a man's job...
不，不，不，請等等！
No, no, no, wait, please!
我不認識塞普蒂默斯，只想搭個便車
I don't know a Septimus. I just need a lift.
看看我…我沒武器，求你
Look at me, Iook at me. I'm unarmed. PIease.
求你，讓我和你一起走
PIease, Iet me ride with you.
恐怕不行，我有重要的事情要辦
I'm afraid that's impossible. I'm on a quest of enormous importance.
那你更應該帶上我了
Well, then all the more reason to take me with you.
必要時你會需要多一雙手來幫你，先生？
There may come a time when you need a second pair of hands. Sir?
求你，命運讓我見到你，就向它讓你見到我一樣
PIease. Maybe providence sent me to you just as it sent you to me.
上來　　　哦，好的，謝謝
-Get on. -Oh, yes. Thank you.
天啊，親愛的，外面這麼大雨，進來吧
Goodness me, my dear. Come in out of this wretched rain!
我們有食物和飲料，溫暖的床
We have food and drink, a warm bed and plenty of hot water for a bath.
還提供充足的熱水供你洗澡
你喜歡怎樣洗？溫水，熱水還是沸水？
How do you like your bath? Warm, hot or boil-a-Iobster?
說實話我也不知道
I honestly don't know.
那我來幫你決定吧
Then Iet me choose for you,
我會讓我的丈夫把你的馬帶到馬房裡
and I'll have my husband take your horse to the stable.
比利？
Billy?
現在，我們幫你把濕衣服脫掉好嗎？
Now, Iet's get you out of your wet things, shall we?
感到好些了嗎？
Feeling better?
好多了，謝謝
Much. Thank you.
溫水實際上讓我很舒服
The warm water's actually done me a world of good.
知道了吧？熱水澡的威力就在這兒
You see? The powers of a nice, hot bath.
你的腿部？感覺好些了嗎？
And your Ieg? Any improvement?
棒極了
That is extraordinary.
我只能做些小事，你感到舒服我很高興
It's the very Ieast I could do. I'm just glad you're feeling better.
你看起來也很快樂的樣子
You seem happier in yourself, too.
我確實感到快樂點，煩惱慢慢消失
I do feel happier. Less troubled.
太棒了
Wonderful.
沒有比泡熱水澡更能溫暖你心中的折皺了
Nothing like a nice soak to warm the cockles of your heart.
現在，我只是個旅館主婦
Now, I'm only a simple innkeeper's wife,
但人們說我有一雙可以幫人療養的手
but I've been told I have a healer's hands.
我可以給你按摩
I'd be glad to give you a massage.
按摩是什麼？
What's a massage?
沒試過…上帝啊
Never had... Well, bless my soul.
沒什麼能使你被按摩後那樣，睡得又香又甜
Nothing like a massage to send you off for the finest and deepest night's sleep.
我確實晚上很難入睡
I do have trouble sleeping at night.
躺下吧，親愛的
Lie on your back, dear.
為什麼不閉上眼睛？
Why not close your eyes?
閉上眼睛可以更快入睡
You'll drift off better that way.
有人嗎！
Hello!
需要服務！
Service!
可能我們應該繼續找下一個旅店
Maybe we should carry on and try the next inn,
如果石頭靠近你的羅盤了，更應該這樣
especially if this stone is as close as your runes say.
我再試一次
I'll give it one more try.
放鬆，親愛的
Relax here, my Iove.
我一接待完客人，就馬上回來
I'll be back just as soon as I've taken care of this customer.
終於，我們需要住宿
At Iast. We require accommodation.
請幫我的朋友把馬帶到馬房裡
PIease help my friend take the horses to the stables.
有人嗎！
Hello!
哦
Oh.
我習慣享用較好的服務
I'm accustomed to better service,
不過既然把你吵醒了，那就這樣吧
but you're awake now and that's what counts.
把最好的客房為我準備好
Prepare your best room.
她戴著寶石　　　寶石，寶石
-She got the stone. -Stone, stone.
謝謝你沒打擾我的客人，先生，我是店主夫人
I'll thank you not to bother my guest, sir. I am the Iady of this inn.
一杯葡萄酒？
GIass of wine?
不，不，不，不，不
No, no, no, no, no.
不
No.
在我兄弟死之前，我發誓只喝我自己的酒
Until my brother is dead, I have vowed to drink only my own wine.
我在外面馬房的朋友可能會喝點
Though my friend in the stables might be glad of a drop.
你最好的客房，有嗎？
Your best room, perhaps?
當然
Of course.
對不起，我假定…
I'm sorry. I presumed that...
獨自旅行，是嗎？
Traveling alone, are you?
我剛把四匹公馬和馬車放在馬房裡
I've just stabled my four black stallions and my carriage.
我說我的，他們是我過世的父親的
Well, I say mine. It belonged to my Iate father.
謝謝
Thank you.
你真好，非常感謝，我叫特裡斯頓，你呢？
That's so kind, thank you very much. My name's Tristan. What's yours?
伯納德
Bernard.
沒什麼馬匹或牲畜…他不能駕御的
There was not a horse or beast he could not master.
他年輕時，曾經去騎一頭駱駝
So much so that in his youth, he took to riding a camel,
顯得非常滑稽
which was comical.
他死後，馬車就歸我了
When he passed, the carriage came to me.
她戴著寶石
She's got the stone!
她戴著寶石　　　她戴著寶石
-She's got it! -She's got it!
他們說是要塞裡最大的馬車
And it's the Iargest in all of Stormhold, so they say.
太棒了，失陪一下
How nice for you. If you'll excuse me.
等等
Wait.
你戴著那個寶石，不可能吧
That stone you're wearing. It can't be.
哦，終於…　　是啊，好的，不錯
-Oh, finally. -Yeah, good, well done, yes, sir.
幹得不錯　　　寶貝
-Well done. -Sweet.
過來，讓我看看
Come here. Let me see it.
你根本不明白你動了誰的東西
You have no idea what you're meddling with.
我是普裡默斯，風暴要塞的老大
I am Primus, the first born of Stormhold and I demand that you bring it to me!
我要求你趕快把它給我
把寶石給我，現在就給我！
Bring me the stone! Now!
普裡默斯王子！
Prince Primus! Don't touch anything they give you! They tried to...
他們給你的任何東西都別碰，他們想…
你還好嗎？　　比利
-Are you all right? -Billy!
抓住他！
Get him!
雖然你那弱小無力的心
The burning golden heart of a star at peace
跟那金子般珍貴的星星之心比起來，不值一提
is so much better than your frightened little heart.
但也總比沒有強
Even so, better than no heart at all.
亞伊尼？抓緊我，心裡想著家
Yvaine? Hold me tight and think of home.
不！
No!
你到底幹了什麼？
-What the hell did you do? -What did I do? What did you do?
我幹了什麼？你到底幹了什麼？
「心裡想著家！」這想法太好了
"Think of home!" That was a great plan!
你想著你的家，而我想著家
You thought of your home and I thought of mine
現在我們在兩個家中間了！
and now we're halfway between the two!
哦，你這頭蠢豬！你想著你的家幹什麼？
Oh, you stupid cow! What did you think of your home for?
你只是說「家」！
You just said "home"!
如果你要我想著你的家，你應該告訴我！
If you wanted me to think of your home, you should have said!
瘋子婦人想把你的心切下來
Some crazy Iady was going to cut your heart out
你需要更詳細的解釋嗎？
and you wanted more specific instructions?
把它寫成書，還是畫成圖解！
Perhaps you'd like it in writing! Or a diagram, maybe!
看，莎士比亞船長！逮住一點戰利品
Look, Captain Shakespeare! Caught ourselves a little bonus!
馬歇爾夫婦
A couple of Lightning Marshals!
我覺得他們不像馬歇爾夫婦
They don't Iook like Lightning Marshals to me.
為什麼有人會跑這麼高到風暴驟雨裡來？
Why else would anyone be up here in the middle of a storm?
「為什麼有人會跑這麼高，到暴風驟雨裡來？」
"Why else would anyone be up here in the middle of a storm?"
那麼，讓我們想想
Well, Iet's think.
大概和我們來這兒是同樣的原因！
Maybe for the same godforsaken reason we are!
現在，你們是誰？
Now, who are you?
讓他們在禁閉室裡舒舒服服住一晚後
Let's see if a night on our Iovely brig will Ioosen their lips!
便會開口說話的！
帶他們去禁閉室！　　聽到嗎！我們進去！
-Get them in the brig! -You heard the man! Let's go!
帶他們去禁閉室！剩下的傢伙回去幹活！
Get them into the brig and the rest of you dirty dogs, back to work!
我們得捕獲更多閃電，快啊！
We've got lightning to catch! Come on!
他們會殺了我們是吧？　　我不知道
-They're going to kill us, aren't they? -I don't know.
你知道，這看來好笑，我習慣看著…
You know, it's funny. I used to watch...
我習慣看著人們進行探險
I used to watch people having adventures.
我嫉妒他們
I envied them.
你聽說過「小心你所期望的東西」嗎？
You ever heard the expression, "Be careful what you wish for"?
什麼？難道是最後切下我的心就滿足了？
What? So ending up with my heart cut out, that'll serve me right, will it?
不，不，我不是…那個意思
No. No, I didn't... I didn't mean it like that.
我很欣賞你在夢想
Look, I admire you dreaming.
我這樣的小店男童
Shop boy like me,
從來沒有想過去做這麼大的探險
I could never have imagined an adventure this big
去實現願望
in order to have wished for it.
我只是想，我會找到天上掉下的那些石頭
I just thought I'd find some Iump of celestial rock
把它帶回家，就這樣
and take it home, and that would be it.
你把我抓住了
And you got me.
在我看著地球的這麼多年裡
If there's one thing I've Iearned in all my years watching Earth,
如果要說一件我學到的東西
那就是人們並不都是象表面看上去的那樣
it's that people aren't what they may seem.
有小店男童
There are shop boys
有些男孩碰巧暫時在小店裡工作
and there are boys who just happen to work in shops for the time being.
相信我，特裡斯頓，你不是小店男童
And trust me, Tristan, you're no shop boy.
你挽救了我的生命，謝謝你
You saved my life. Thank you.
不錯，不錯，不錯
Well, well, well.
最後一個兄弟死了
The Iast brother dead.
也就是說我是國王了
Which means that I'm king.
我是國王！
I'm king!
還不是，兄弟
Not yet, brother.
該死，我還得拿到寶石
Damn. I still need the stone.
你兄弟沒拿到嗎？
-Your brother doesn't have it? -Well, why don't you find out?
那你為什麼不去找到它？
我的寶石在哪？
Where is my stone?
我不…
I don't...
那個人，知道嗎，就是你兄弟
The man, see, your brother... I heard him speak of a stone.
我聽到他談到寶石
是的，在女孩那，在女孩那
Yeah. The girl had it. The girl had it.
什麼女孩？　　我不知道
-What girl? -I don't know.
一個女孩，她走了，這都是給她做的陷阱
A girl. She got away. Because this was a trap set up for her,
但你兄弟，他直接走進陷阱裡
but your brother, he come just straight into it.
陷阱？誰做的？
A trap? Set by who?
一個你祈禱永遠也不願見到的女人
A woman you should pray you'll never meet.
她已經…
She's...
她已經走了，她帶走了你兄弟的馬車
She's gone. She took your brother's carriage.
這個女人要我的石頭嗎？
This woman wanted my stone?
不是，她要那個女孩的心
No. She wanted the girl's heart.
她說那個女孩是個星星，她要切下她的心
She said the girl was a star and she wanted to cut out her heart and...
吃掉
Eat it?
哦，我的天
Oh, my God.
你知道這意味著什麼嗎？
Do you have any idea what this means?
永恆的生命
Everlasting life.
永遠的國王
King forever.
不在裡面，陛下
It's not here, sire.
這個蠢貨和我們一起去
This idiot's coming with us.
再問問　　　我們已經問過了
-Ask again. -We have asked again
答案是同樣的，她是空中傳送的！
and the answer is still the same. She is airborne!
那麼，她不可能永遠這樣
Well, she can't remain so forever.
她一旦到地上立刻通知我！
Inform me as soon as she touches ground!
立刻！你懂了嗎？
Immediately! Do you understand?
注意你的語氣，姐姐！
Watch your tongue, sister! It is you and not we who've Iost her.
是你把她弄丟了，而不是我們
把她弄丟了，把刀也弄斷了！
Lost her and broken the knife!
即使你逮住她，你如何把她的心切下來？
Even if you apprehend her, how will you complete the deed?
也許你現在該回來
Perhaps you should return now and one of us set out in your place.
然後由我們姐妹中的一個取代你的位置
別胡說了
Don't be absurd.
我會把她帶回來，在那就把她處理好
I'll bring her home and deal with her there.
最好在我回來時，看到一切都準備就緒了
Be sure everything is ready for our arrival.
告訴我一點關於維多利亞的故事
Tell me about Victoria then.
她…
Well, she...
沒什麼可說的
There's nothing more to tell you.
我對愛不太懂，但我知道它是無條件的
Because the little I know about Iove is that it's unconditional.
它不是什麼你可以買到的
It's not something you can buy.
等等，不是我去買她的愛
Hang on. This wasn't about me buying her Iove.
我只是用一種方式來證明我對她的感受
This was a way for me to prove how I felt.
那為了證明她對你的感受，她又做了什麼？
And what's she doing to prove how she feels about you?
嗯…
Well...
亞伊尼，當你看到她時你就會懂了，好嗎？
Look, Yvaine, you'll understand when you meet her. All right?
前提是我們不被海盜殺掉
Provided we don't get murdered by pirates first.
被海盜殺掉，心被淘出來吃掉，認識維多利亞
Murdered by pirates. Heart torn out and eaten. Meet Victoria.
我不知道哪個聽起來更好玩
I can't quite decide which sounds more fun.
我們已經知道飛船在哪了
We've Iocated the sky vessel.
她正向著北部倫敦德裡的港口小鎮飛去
It's headed north for the port town on Mount Drummond
你們不再是唯一正在追蹤星星的人了
and you are no Ionger the only one seeking the star.
有個人也跟著你去了！
There's someone following your tracks!
一個女巫？一個術士？
A witch? A warlock?
一個王子，他正追上你！趕快前進吧！
A prince and he's catching you up! Get a move on!
那現在時候到了，你們得告訴我你們是誰
So, this is the part where you tell me who you are and why you're up here.
你們為什麼跑到天上來
不然我會像吃棒棒糖一樣
Or I'll snap her pretty little fingers one by one like dry twigs!
去一根一根地咬她可愛的小指頭
我叫特裡斯頓·索朗
My name is Tristan Thorn.
她是我妻子，亞伊尼　　　你妻子？
-This is my wife, Yvaine. -Your wife?
這麼年輕閃亮，卻只嫁了一個男人
Far too young and radiant to belong to just one man!
在我的船上，東西是要分享的，小傢伙！
It's share and share alike aboard my vessel, sonny boy!
如果你敢碰它…
If you dare even touch her...
你自以為是在女友面前顯示勇氣嗎
You may think you're showing a little spirit in front of your Iady friend,
如果你再頂嘴，我就把你舌頭拿去餵狗
but if you talk back to me again, I'll feed your tongue to the dogs,
你這個鹵莽的傻小子！
you impertinent little pup!
先生？　　好點了！但不要打斷我說話！
-Sir? -Better! But still interrupting.
讓我們看看，絞刑對鼓舞士氣很有好處！
Let's see. A hanging's always good for morale!
也許我們會讓你跳一段絞架舞！
Maybe we'll watch you dance a gallows jig!
或者我直接把你掉過來頭撞地完事！
Or perhaps I'll just tip you over the side and have done with it!
下地獄了還有很長的路要走
It's a very Iong way down.
你有足夠的時間去回憶你痛苦短暫的一生
PIenty of time to reminisce about your pitifully short lives.
求你，我們只不過是想回到家鄉
PIease, Iook, we're just trying to make our way home,
就是叫石牆的地方，我從那來的
back to a place called Wall, where I come from.
你說什麼？
What did you say?
我說我們只想回家到石牆那兒去
I said we were trying to get home to Wall.
你在說謊，我的孩子
That's one lie too many, my son.
石牆　　　閉嘴
-Wall? -Shut up.
他在說什麼？
What's he saying?
你以為你可以在我的地盤撒野，是嗎？
Thought you could just wander onto my patch, did you?
是的，他要…　　活著講故事？
-He is. Yeah, he's gonna... -And live to tell the tale?
好了，走，上甲板去…現在，走…
All right, go, on the deck, on the deck, on the deck! Now, go, go, go!
你錯了，索朗先生！最後一個你說不出來的！
Big mistake, Mr. Thorn! And the Iast one you'll ever make!
不！不！你個畜生！　　來…來吧！
-No! No! You brute! -Come... Come on!
你是殺人犯，你是豬！　　快！起來…
-You murderer! You pig! -Come on! Get up! Get up!
我要把女孩帶到我船艙裡去，照我說的做
I'm taking the girl to my cabin, and mark my words,
接下來幾個小時打擾我的人…
anyone who disturbs me for the next few hours
會和她一樣！　　什麼？你要…
-will get the same treatment! -What? You'll...
不，你個蠢貨！我會把你也吊起來
No, you idiot! I'll sling you over the side as well!
哦，好的
Oh, yeah.
船長很忙，所以你們應該…
Captain's busy. So should you be.
進去，蕩婦！
Get in there, wench!
所以，我覺得演得不錯
So, that went well, I thought.
現在，告訴我有關我心愛英格蘭的消息
Now, tell me news of my beloved England.
那兒的一切我都想知道
I want to hear absolutely everything.
等等，我不敢相信，你的船員就那樣掉下去
Hang on. I can't believe your crew fell for that.
天啊！你是從哪變出那麼一具人體模型來的
And where in God's name did you get that mannequin from?
哦，總是這樣的
Oh, it works every time.
和船員小商量一下，來一點計謀
An ounce of bargaining, a pinch of trickery,
再稍稍威脅他們一下
a soupcon of intimidation, et voila!
想獲得傑出聲望
The perfect recipe for a towering reputation
又不用流一滴血，這就是最好辦法
without ever having to spill one drop of blood.
試過把血漬從絲衫上洗掉嗎？簡直是惡夢
Ever try to get blood stains out of a silk shirt? Nightmare.
是啊，我還是不明白為什麼他們沒認出我來
Right. I still don't understand how they won't recognize me.
特裡斯頓，親愛的孩子，化完妝後
Tristan, dear boy, when I'm done,
連你媽也不會認出你來
your own mother won't recognize you.
我們沒有多少時間了
Now, we've no time to waste.
我們只剩兩小時時間到達港口
We have only two hours before we make port.
首要的事情
First and foremost...
能看到你們脫掉一身舊衣服就再好不過了
It'll be so good to see you out of those dreary clothes.
所以，荒良偏僻小城的男僕
So very small-town errand-boy. Howlingly parochial.
來，穿上試試
Here. Tres you.
都是我年輕時穿的，我一直留著
I wore it as a younger man. I hate to throw anything away.
你穿衣服那一刻，它們又會流行起來
You know the day you do, it'll come back in fashion,
就又成為時尚
be oh, so de la mode-
至於你，親愛的
Now, you, darling.
我也有些適合你的，自己挑吧
I have some Iovely dresses. Take your pick.
哦，是嗎，我不用
Oh, no, really, I'm fine.
寶貝，你穿著一件浴袍到處跑
Honey, you're wearing a bathrobe.
英格蘭，英格蘭，我想知道你的一切
Now, England, England. I want to hear everything.
你不是英格蘭人　　　很不幸，不是…
-You're not from England. -Oh, no, sadly, no.
我年輕時就聽說過那裡的故事
But from my earliest youth, I Iapped up the stories.
人們告訴我，都只不過是些民間傳說
People always told me they were nothing more than folklore,
我的內心卻告訴我那些傳說是真的
but my heart told me they were true.
我還是個孩子時，便從父親身邊跑掉
As a boy, I'd scurry away from my father at the market
父親就為了看看石牆裡面，去和人做交易
while he did his deals just to peek over the wall,
我夢想著有一天能穿過石牆，親眼看看英格蘭
dream of, perhaps, crossing it one day, seeing England for myself.
真的？所以你人在這兒，心裡卻想著那兒
Really? So you... You were here Iooking over there.
是的
Oh, yes.
頭髮　　　頭髮？
-Hair. -Hair?
你知道嗎，我盡力來扮演我的角色
Mind you, I did my best to fit in.
以我父親「魔鬼製造者」船長為榮耀
Tried to make my father, Captain Ghostmaker, proud.
用冷血無情的殺戮
Forged a decent reputation as a ruthless marauder
來樹立自己正義的形象
and cold-blooded killer.
我父親卻死去了
But my father died.
我對他承諾，我會接管家族事業
I always promised him I'd take over the family business,
老女人也得保有活力
keep the old girl flying.
你們知道，能一吐心扉我多開心嗎？
You have no idea the lightness it brings to my heart
能對可愛的年輕人說出真心話
being able to confide in you charming young people.
為了船員們，我又得扮演莎士比亞船長
The pressure of maintaining the whole Captain Shakespeare persona
壓力之大，我不知道該怎麼說
for the sake of the crew, I don't know.
有時…
Sometimes...
知道嗎，我是自己塑造自己的一類人
You see, I'm very much a man of my own creation.
特別是叫這名字之後，幾十年苦心經營它
Even chose the name specially. Took me ages.
當我心裡想著英國傳奇語言藝術家時
See, I'm thinking Iegendary British wordsmith.
我的船員和敵人們卻想著「砍人！戳矛！」
My enemies and crew are thinking, "Shake! Spear!"
談起這些事能讓我高興點
It's little things like that make me happy.
我不明白
I don't understand that.
想快樂點就應該做回你自己
Surely it would make you happier just to be yourself.
你不想做這樣的人，卻為什麼要…
Why fight to be accepted by people you don't actually want to be like?
如此辛苦地讓人們接受你成為這樣的人？
是啊，誰會這樣對待自己？
Yeah. Why would anyone do that to himself?
確實是
Exactly.
嘿，港口，準備好桶裝酒迎接我們！
Port ahoy! Ready the lightning barrels!
快點
Hurry up.
對，看起來不算很奇特，我會說實價的
Yeah. Doesn't seem very fresh. I'll be honest.
想體驗一下它嗎？年輕的費迪南得？
Shall I give you a little taste, young Ferdinand?
不，不用，哦，看這個
No, no. Oh, there you go.
絢麗！不過還是廉價貨
Brilliant. Like they're cheap.
我認為這玩意異常活躍，也很奇特
I think it's still crackling, very much alive, still tres fresh.
那開個好價吧　　　一萬個螺栓的價？
-So, name your best price. -For 10,000 bolts?
A等品的一萬個螺栓嗎？
Ten thousand bolts of finest quality grade A.
是的，但這玩意還不好挪放
Yeah, but it's difficult to shift, isn't it? Difficult to store.
如果被嗅覺靈敏的收稅人看到了
If I get the Revenue Men in here sniffing round, what's the...
給你個最好的價，150鎊
Best price, 150 guineas.
夥計們，把貨放回船上準備起航
Gentlemen, put the merchandise back onboard and prepare to sail.
哦…　　費迪南得，交談愉快
-Whoa, whoa, whoa. -Ferdinand, always a pleasure.
等等，等等，一分鐘，等等，親愛的
Hold on. Hold on. One minute. Hold on, cuddles.
160鎊，160鎊
-Oh, he's... -One-sixty. One-sixty.
你知道我今天特別的慷慨
Seeing as I'm feeling particularly generous today,
200鎊更很合適點
I'll settle for 200.
200鎊？好吧，你在開玩笑？
Two hundred? Okay. You're having a Iaugh.
你把頭插在這裡面過嗎？
Have you had your head in that?
還是呆在空氣稀薄的地方太久了？
Has he been sailing up where the air's too thin?
你說話很粗魯　　　我不說了
-You're being very rude. -Not anymore.
200鎊　　　180鎊
-Two hundred. -One-eighty.
200鎊　　　談判不是這樣的
-Two hundred. -That's not negotiation.
我改變價格吧
I'm changing my number. One-eight-five.
我聽到的是200嗎？　　那是你嘴裡說的
-Did I hear 200? -From you, you did. Yeah.
你說的200　　　我說的？那你就是口技演員
-You said 200. -If I did, you're a ventriloquist.
好吧，195鎊，最後出價
Okay, one-nine-five. Final offer.
是195鎊，加上成交稅，那就是200
One-nine-five it is. So, with sales tax, that's, Iet's see, 200.
算你狠，拿到後面去吧
Brilliant. Put it in the back.
難以置信，來
Unbelievable. Here.
有事嗎？要我幫忙嗎？
Yes? Can I help you?
管閒事
Nosy.
你在附近聽說過墜落流星的傳言嗎？
Have you heard any of these rumors going round about a fallen star?
人人都在談論這個
Everyone's talking about it.
能找到那些星星的話，就可以退休養老了
You get your hands on one of them, we can shut up shop. Retire.
墜落的流星？　　是啊
-Fallen star? -Yeah.
旅行時沒聽說過？　　沒有
-Nothing on your travels? -No.
一點傳聞都沒聽到過？
Not even a little sniff of a whisper?
市場裡人人都在談論這個？
Everyone's going on about it down at the market.
哪個市場？石牆附近的市場嗎？
Which market? The market near the wall?
是的
Yeah.
費迪，市場裡總有些池塘浮渣交易
Well, Ferdy, you're wasting your time listening to gossip
去聽這些流言蜚語是浪費時間
from the kind of pond scum trading down there.
哦，我的嘴巴，在這亂說
-Well, if it... -Oh, my word! Speak of the devil.
哦，是嗎？那你們在說什麼？
Oh, yeah? What were you saying, then?
我在說你是多麼能幹的主婦啊，莎爾
Oh, what a wonderful woman you are, Sal.
沒有你世界就完全是另一個樣子了
How the world wouldn't be the same place without you.
你氣色不錯，你把腳弄好了，是吧？
You Iook great. You've had your feet done, haven't you?
但你們倆有事要談吧，莎爾，費迪，再見
But, you two, you have business to attend to. Sal. Ferdy. Good day.
走吧，我有新東西給你看
Come on. I've got something new for you.
莎士比亞船長
Captain Shakespeare.
停戰！
Stand down!
認識下我的外甥，可怕的海盜
Meet my nephew, the fearsome buccaneer,
特裡斯頓·索朗
Tristan Thorn.
他將加入我們返回老家的旅程
He'll be joining us for our journey home.
我送你個禮物，讓你在路上玩得開心
I have the perfect gift to keep you amused on the way.
哦
Oh...
右邊，大懶狗！
Right, you Iazy dogs!
讓我們帶著年輕的特裡斯頓回家吧
Let's get young Tristan on his way home!
不賴嘛
Touche.
給我印象深刻
I'm impressed.
亞伊尼，我知道你是什麼
Yvaine, I know what you are.
不，不，別害怕
No, no. Have no fear.
這裡沒人會傷害你
No one on this vessel will harm you, but there are plenty who would.
但其他地方有很多人想傷害你
你的不安情緒流露出來，亞伊尼
Your emotions give you away, Yvaine. You must Iearn to control them.
你得學會控制才行
每天你都不斷變得更加光亮
You've been glowing more brightly every day,
我想你知道為什麼會這樣
and I think you know why.
我當然知道我為什麼變得光亮，我是顆星星
Of course I know why I'm glowing. I'm a star.
星星最擅長什麼？　　當然不是跳華爾茲了
-And what do stars do best? -Well, it's certainly not the waltz.
再試試　　　好的
-Now try. -Okay.
看到了嗎？　　非常好
-See? -Very good.
你說正西方嗎？
Due west, you say?
你確定還有個女孩和他在一起？
And you're certain he had a girl with him?
是的
Yeah.
你確定？完全肯定？確定你沒有撒謊？
You're sure? Absolutely sure? Sure you're not Iying?
如果撒謊我會在胸口劃十字
I'd cross my heart if I had one.
漂亮　　　你最好說的是實話
-Brilliant. -You'd better be telling the truth,
你這個雙面狗
you two-faced dog.
其實你可以給自己弄一隻很好的看門狗
I can get you one of them, actually. Very good guard dogs.
他們可以同時看到前方和背後
They can watch the back and the front door at the same time.
我要什麼我都可以給你
I can get you anything you want.
我得到巴比倫蠟燭的機率是多少？
What are the chances of getting a Babylon candle?
那個機率不大
That one's slim.
儘管這樣，我還是認識一個女孩
AIthough, I did know a girl once, if you know what I mean...
如果你知道我是說誰的話…
我喜歡追女人
I'm a Iadies' man.
這女孩有個姐姐
...who had a sister...
我想應該是個婦女
I think it was a woman.
哦，她看起來很可怕
Oh, she was terrible. Face like a bag of frogs. Ugly frogs.
青蛙一般的臉，醜陋的青蛙
夠了
Enough.
抓緊了，船長在掌舵
Hold on tight! The Captain's at the helm!
那邊就是通向石牆的路
So there's the road you'll need for Wall.
無論回家的旅程將會怎樣，祝你一路順風
Good Iuck on your journey home, Yvaine, wherever that may be.
祝你和維多利亞好運
And good Iuck to you, Tristan, with your Victoria.
我該怎麼回報你的好意呢？
Oh, how can we ever thank you enough for your kindness?
別這麼說，說真的，別提它
Don't mention it. No, seriously, don't mention it.
你知道名聲這東西嗎？
Reputations, you know. A lifetime to build, seconds to destroy.
用一生的時間去建立，片刻就可以毀掉
哦，特裡斯頓，記住…
Oh, and Tristan, just remember...
好好去想想
Just think about it.
那麼，幫我帶去給英格蘭的問候
Well, give my regards to England. It's been a pleasure to meet you both.
見到你們兩位是我的榮幸
別讓那蕩婦累著了，特裡斯頓船長！
Mind you don't wear that wench out, Captain Tristan!
他對你說了什麼？
What did he say to you?
他什麼時候說什麼了？
What did he say when?
就是他和你說悄悄話的時候
Just then. When he whispered to you.
不…他…就說我們應該利用閃電
No... No, he... He was just saying we should use the lightning
來給你做個巴比倫蠟燭
to get you a Babylon candle.
以物換物，你知道嗎
Barter for it, you know.
最後說一遍，那女孩在哪？
For the Iast time, where is the girl?
帶著寶石的女孩！她去哪了？
The girl with the stone! Where did she go?
你在嘲笑我嗎？　　不
-Are you mocking me? -No...
相信我，如果你嘲笑我，你小命就只有幾秒了！
'Cause if you are, believe me, you have seconds to live!
這隻怪物
What a freak.
清洗乾淨，徹底點
CIean this thoroughly.
小公牛
Bollocks.
如果你不把魔法浪費在讓你變美
If you have quite finished squandering your magic
這種不可能的事情上
on your rather counterproductive beauty routine,
你應該會知道星星已經回來了
you might like to know that the star has returned.
她回到地面了
She's back on Iand.
我知道，該死的，我沒能及時趕到湖泊那
I know, damn it. I couldn't reach the Iake in time.
沒關係，我們已經找到她了
No matter. We have found her. She is on the road to the village of Wall.
她在去石牆村莊的路上
如果你走近路穿過沼澤
If you take the shortcut across the marshes,
你應該可以及時趕到並攔截住她
you should arrive in time to intercept her.
亞伊尼
Yvaine.
你又想把我的腿摔斷嗎？　　對不起…
-Are you trying to break my Ieg again? -I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
我只是不想讓人看到你，我不信任何人
I just... I can't risk people seeing you. I don't trust anyone.
但現在的速度，如果我們老是停下…
But at this rate, if we keep stopping...
亞伊尼，我們一起很快樂，就等一會
Yvaine. We're making good time. Just Ieave it a minute.
你不是被吸引住了吧？
Aren't you tempted?
吸引？被什麼吸引了？
Tempted? By what?
永恆的生命
Immortality.
我希望不是我的心
Let's say it wasn't my heart.
不是我，我只是一顆無名的星星
Not me. Just a star you didn't know.
你真的認為我會殺人嗎？
You seriously think I could kill anyone?
我是說，為了得到永恆生命？
I mean, even if I could... Everlasting life?
我想那樣我反倒會孤獨
I imagine it would be kind of Ionely.
所以
Well,
如果可以和一個人，一個你愛的人
maybe if you had someone to share it with.
去分享那份生命
Someone you Iove.
那可能就不一樣了
Maybe then it might be different.
來吧，我想現在安全了
Come on, I think we're safe.
記住，莎士比亞船長有個非常可怕的名聲
Now remember, Captain Shakespeare has a fearsome reputation.
這是怎麼回事？　　你進來幹什麼？
-What the hell is this? -What are you doing here?
我的是塞普蒂默斯王子
My name is Prince Septimus.
你來告訴我那女孩在哪
And you're going to tell me where I can find the girl.
好了，光腳丫，我數三下，一、二…
All right, twinkletoes. I'm gonna count to three. One, two...
你知道，你有時閃閃發光的
You know, you sort of glitter sometimes. I just noticed it. Is it normal?
我剛注意到，是正常現象嗎？
你自己想想看
Let's see if you can work it out for yourself.
星星會怎樣？
What do stars do?
給人添麻煩嗎？
Attract trouble?
好了，對不起，等等我，對不起
That's... All right, I'm sorry. Wait, I'm sorry.
好了，讓我…讓我…再猜猜
All right, Iet me... Let me... Do I get another guess?
星星知道怎麼讓一個…
Is it... Do they know exactly how to annoy a boy called Tristan Thorn?
叫特裡斯頓·索朗的男孩煩惱嗎？
（ 距離石牆60英里 ）
還有多遠？　　可能要兩天
-How Iong will that take? -Maybe two days.
但我們時間有限，明天是維多利亞的生日
But we don't have two days. Victoria's birthday is tomorrow.
是啊，記得真準啊
Yes, it is. Well remembered.
一杯美味的伯爵茶　　　出去，都出去
-Nice cup of Earl Grey. -Get out, everybody. Get out.
他傷到你了嗎，船長？
Did he hurt you, Captain?
你告訴他…你外甥和那女孩去哪了嗎？
Did you tell him where your nephew and the girl went?
那麼到底出了什麼問題？
So what's the problem?
是關於我的名聲
It's my reputation.
不，不，別說傻話
No. No, no. Don't be silly. Nonsense.
沒事的，船長
It's all right, Captain.
我們都知道你喜歡男人
We always knew you were a whoopsie.
你永遠是我們的船長，船長　　　船長
-You'll always be our captain, Captain. -Aye, aye, Captain.
船長
Captain.
我們走，我們走
Yeah. Let's go, Iet's go.
塞普蒂默斯王子，你的部下都死了
Prince Septimus, your men, they're dead.
哦，真的嗎？
Oh, really?
走
Go on!
我見過那個女人，她是船長的朋友
I met that woman. She's friends with the Captain.
他說她在石牆附近的市場做生意
He said she trades at the market near Wall.
我們搭順風車　　　真的？她是船長朋友？
-We could hitch a lift. -Really? She's a friend of the Captain's?
你確定？　　是的，是的
-You sure? -Yes, yes.
等等！對不起！我叫特裡斯頓·索朗，她是…
Wait! Sorry! My name is Tristan Thorn. This...
那是我的花
That's my flower.
18年了，我一直在找她
Eighteen years I've been Iooking for that.
快給我！
Give it to me now!
你怎麼敢？那是她媽媽給她的禮物！
How dare you? That was a gift from his mother!
哦
Oh.
我可能誤解了
Perhaps I was mistaken.
沒事
It's all right.
它對你顯然很有價值，我可以給你
It's obviously very valuable to you, so you can have it
幫我個忙以作為交換
in exchange for what I need.
給我巴比倫蠟燭？　　護送我們去石牆
-A Babylon candle? -And safe passage to the wall.
巴比倫蠟燭？
A Babylon candle?
哦，不，不…我不和黑暗魔法打交道
Oh, no, no, no. I don't deal in black magic.
是嗎？
Really?
那你能送我們一程去石牆嗎？
Well, can you give us a lift then? To the wall?
你怎麼不早說？
Well, why didn't you say so in the first place?
為了那朵花，我可以送你一程
For that flower, I can offer you passage.
路上需要食宿嗎？　　旅程安全就行
-Food and Iodging on the way? -Safe passage.
我發誓，你會像現在這個樣子
I swear that you will arrive at the wall
安全到達石牆
in the exact same condition that you're in now.
你知道這花是什麼東西嗎？
Do you have any idea what manner of thing it was that you had?
某種幸運的魔法？
Some kind of Iucky charm?
一個好運的防護魔法
A very Iucky charm indeed. Protection.
實際上，為了防護，我本不想這麼做
In fact, the exact same thing that would've prevented me from doing this.
哦，天那，你幹了什麼？　　好多了
-Oh, my God! What did you do? -Much better.
你不能看她，碰她，嗅她，聽她
You shall not see the star, touch it, smell or hear it-
我會遵守諾言，你不會受到傷害
Though I'll keep me word. You shall not be harmed.
去那裡面，食宿就和我保證的一樣
There. Food and Iodging just as I promised.
你既看不見我，也聽不到我，我說的對嗎？
Would I be correct in thinking that you can neither see nor hear me?
我想告訴你，你身上一股尿味
Then I'd like to tell you that you smell of pee.
你看起來像個卑鄙小人
You Iook like the wrong end of a dog.
我發誓，如果特裡斯頓變不回去
And I swear, if I don't get my Tristan back as he was,
我做鬼也要永遠纏著你
I'll be your personal poltergeist!
（ 距離石牆60英里 ）
特裡斯頓？
Tristan?
如果你能聽懂我說話，請看著我
If you can understand me, Iook at me now.
你知道嗎，當我說…我不懂愛情的時候
You know when I said I knew little about Iove?
那不是真的
Well, that wasn't true.
關於愛情我知道很多
I know a Iot about Iove.
我看到過了，看了幾百年了
I've seen it. I've seen centuries and centuries of it.
唯一能支撐我繼續看著人類世界的就是愛
And it was the only thing that made watching your world bearable.
所有的戰爭、痛苦、謊言、仇恨
All those wars. Pain and lies. Hate.
這些東西讓我想轉過頭去，不再往下看
Made me want to turn away and never Iook down again.
我就是來看人類是如何愛的
But to see the way that mankind Ioves.
我是說，你可以到遙遠世界的深處去尋找
I mean, you could search the furthest reaches of the universe
卻找不到比愛更美的東西
and never find anything more beautiful.
所以，是的，我知道愛是無條件的
So, yes, I know that Iove is unconditional.
但我也知道愛是不可預知的
But I also know it can be unpredictable,
無法預料的，無發控制的，無法忍受的
unexpected, uncontrollable, unbearable
奇怪的是，愛很容易被錯認為是憎惡
and, well, strangely easy to mistake for Ioathing.
And
特裡斯頓 我想說的是…
what I'm trying to say, Tristan, is
我認為我愛上你了
I think I Iove you.
我的身體幾乎不能容納我的心了
My heart, it feels like my chest can barely contain it.
好像它不再屬於我了，而是屬於你
Like it doesn't belong to me anymore. It belongs to you.
如果你要的話，我會無償地給你
And if you wanted it, I'd wish for nothing in exchange.
不需要禮物，不需要商品
No gifts, no goods, no demonstrations of devotion.
不必讓我看到你所投入的
什麼都不需要，我只要你也愛我
Nothing but knowing you Iove me, too.
就是你的心…
Just your heart
換取我的心
in exchange for mine.
石牆在那個方向一里處
The wall is one mile that way.
儘管步行將花去比一般更長的時間
There. Though the walk might take you a little Ionger than normal.
變回原樣，會使你頭腦發暈一段時間
Transformation tends to Ieave the brain a bit scrambled for a while.
你…
You...
哦！
Oh!
我警告過你了，省點力氣吧
I warned you. Save your strength.
我一直都在擔心你
I've been so worried about you.
維多利亞
Victoria.
我寧願你叫我「母親」
I think I preferred "Mother."
來吧，那邊有個客棧
Come on. There's an inn over there. Victoria's birthday's not till tomorrow.
維多利亞的生日要明天才到
你把我送給她之前
I think you need a bath and a good night's sleep
你需要洗個澡好好睡一覺
before you present me to her.
來吧，來
Come on. Come.
來吧，特裡斯頓，不遠了　　　好的
-Come on, Tristan. It's not that far. -Okay.
對不起？　　哦
-Excuse me? -Oh!
我認為你躺在我的浴室裡了　　　閉上眼！
-I think you're in my bath. -Well, close your eyes!
我不是…老實說，我沒有看
I'm not... Honestly, I'm not Iooking. Here, I'll turn away.
在這，我轉過身了
好了，你可以睜開了
All right, you can open them now.
你在大篷車裡說的都是真的嗎？
Did you really mean what you said in the caravan?
我…
What I...
但是…你那時是隻老鼠！
But... But you were a mouse!
你是隻老鼠！你只想吃奶酪！你沒有…
You were a mouse! You wanted cheese! You didn't...
我要你對我示意
I asked you to give me a sign.
說出如此富有愛意的話來，覺得不好意思了？
And risk you being too embarrassed to keep saying such Iovely things?
你想知道船長真正對我說了些什麼悄悄話嗎？
You want to know what the Captain really whispered to me that day?
他告訴我，真愛就在我的眼前
He told me that my true Iove was right in front of my eyes.
他說的對
And he was right.
夥計們…過來！你們得看看這個
Hey, guys! Guys, come on! Come on, you got to come up and see this!
不，謝謝
No, thank you.
變態！　　隨便你們
-Pervert! -Suit yourself.
有點諷刺，是嗎？　　是啊，什麼？
-Ironic, isn't it? -Yeah. What is?
塞普蒂默斯早上就會到這兒
Septimus will be here by the morning,
找到女孩，拿到寶石，永遠成為國王
find the girl, get the stone and be king forever.
太不公平了
So unjust.
儘管這樣，我們卻自由了
Still, at Ieast we will be free.
你離她很近了，她就在鎮集裡
You're very close. She's in the market town.
離石牆缺口一英里處
One mile from the gap in the wall.
說起來好像是條好消息
You speak as if this is good news.
要我提醒你們嗎？
Do I need to remind you that Wall is not part of our universe?
那堵牆不屬於這個世界的一部分
如果她穿過石牆入口、進入人類領地
If she crosses the threshold into the human realm,
她只會變成一塊泛著金屬光澤的石頭
our star becomes nothing more than a pitted Iump of metallic rock.
那麼我建議你快點！
Then I suggest you hurry up!
什麼？
What?
哦，你要什麼？
Oh, what do you want?
對不起，能給我一張紙和一隻筆嗎？
Sorry. Can I have a piece of paper and a pen?
在合適的時間再來問我
Ask me again at a more reasonable hour.
不，不行，我得走了
No, I can't. I have to go.
我回來前如果我的朋友醒了
Look, if my friend wakes up before I get back,
請你幫我帶個口信給她好嗎？　　說吧
-please, can you give her a message? -Go on.
你知道，這是我第一次在夜晚睡著了
You know, that's the first time I've ever slept at night.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
特裡斯頓?
Tristan?
你看到我朋友了嗎？
Have you seen my friend?
他很奇怪地一大早就離開了
He Ieft absurdly early.
他走了？
He Ieft?
他讓我告訴你他去見維多利亞了
He told me to tell you he's gone to see Victoria
因為他很抱歉，但他已經找到了真愛
because he's sorry, but he's found his true Iove
他想餘生和她一起度過
and he wants to spend the rest of his life with her.
什麼？
What?
你確定嗎？　　我肯定
-Are you sure? -I'm positive.
嘿！嘿，等等！等等！
Hey! Hey, wait! Wait!
生日快樂
Happy birthday.
特裡斯頓
Tristan.
發生什麼了？
What happened to you?
我找到了那顆星星
I found the star.
我不相信你居然做到了
I can't believe you did it.
我的星星呢？我能看看嗎？
Where's my star? Can I see it?
它漂亮嗎？　　是的
-Is it beautiful? -Yes.
但它卻這麼小
Well, it's awfully small.
那只是一小片，作為你生日的紀念品
Well, that's just a little piece. A token for your birthday.
那麼…忘掉星星吧
Well... Well, then forget about the star.
這不是我要的星星
It's not the star that I want.
你知道我想要什麼
You know what I want.
是的，我知道
Yeah. I do.
你想長大，過完這輩子
You want to grow up and get over yourself.
漢弗萊　　　索朗
-Humphrey. -Thorn.
你大概是想死了
You must have a death wish.
漢弗萊，漢弗萊，沒事
Humphrey. Humphrey, it's all right.
她是你的
She's all yours.
你們是天造地設的一對，衷心祝福你們
You really are a perfect couple. The best of Iuck to you both.
那麼，我要這個幹什麼？
Well, why would I want this? It's just a measly handful of stardust!
這只是一把微不足道的星塵！
亞伊尼？
Yvaine?
她不能穿過石牆
She can't cross the wall.
快！
Go on!
站住！站住！如果你穿過那你會死的！
Stop! Stop! If you go through there, you'll die!
什麼？
What?
如果你踏上人類的領地，你會變成石頭
If you set foot on human soil, you'll turn to rock.
可悲骯髒的女人！你把我帶哪來了？
Wretched slattern! Where have you taken me?
準備進入石牆了是嗎？
PIanning to enter Wall, were you?
如果你願意死，親愛的，我很樂意幫你
If death is what you wish, my dear, I'd be more than happy to assist you.
你在和我說話？
Are you talking to me?
你，小城民
You. Small world.
總之，不，我沒和你說話，我在和星星說話
Anyhow, no, I wasn't. I was talking to the star.
什麼星星？
What star?
我的女奴不是星星，傻瓜也看得出來
My slave girl's no star. Any fool can see that.
如果她是的話，我很久以前…
If she was, I'd have had the heart out of her chest
就把她的心挖出來了，相信我
a Iong time ago, trust me.
相信你？我不想再犯錯誤了
Trust you? Not a mistake I'd be likely to make again.
想怎麼樣，臨死的莎爾？擲銅板決定？
What's it to be, Ditchwater Sal? Heads or tails?
哦，天啊，我們該走了　　　她哪也不去
-Oh, God. Time to go. -She's not going anywhere.
我想你會知道她是誰的
I think you'll find she is.
沒事，你也可以去
It's all right. You can come, too.
你們可以坐馬車或拖在馬車後，自己選吧
You can ride in the carriage or be dragged behind it. Your choice.
剛才發生什麼了？
What happened?
請便客人，我退出
Be my guest. I quit.
80年了，我防止人們從這出去
Eighty years I've stopped you people going out.
但是我該更加擔心的是
What I should have been worrying about
有些人會從裡面跑出來
was those people from the other side coming in.
好吧，快告訴我發生什麼了！
All right, just tell me what happened!
發生什麼？哦，從哪說起呢？
What happened? Oh, where to start?
不！
No!
快！
Come on!
Go on!
星星！
The star!
這位是誰？
And who else?
是我們的奴隸，當我們招呼完客人後
A slave for us. It will be nice to have someone to help mop up
她可以幫我們好好打掃衛生了
when we've finished with our little guest.
哦，對我們有好處，姐妹
Oh, good work, sister.
很及時啊，我明白了！你越來越難看了！
And just in time, I see! You Iook awful!
你是誰？
Who are you?
你來這兒做什麼？
What business do you have here?
塞普蒂默斯？
Septimus?
我認識你哥哥，普裡默斯
I knew your brother, Primus.
你是不是想去地獄見他？
Unless you wish to meet him in the afterlife,
我建議你快回答我，你在這幹什麼？
I suggest you answer my question. What are you doing here?
我也想問你同樣的問題
I might ask you the same thing.
他們有四個人
There are four of them.
照我說的做我們應該有機會
Do as I say and we may stand a chance.
等等，我為什麼要相信你？
Wait. How do I know you can be trusted?
你不用，為什麼？你還有更好的選擇嗎？
You don't. Why? Do you have a choice?
沒有　　　那好，我們走
-No. -Well, then, Iet's go.
走開！走開！
Get off me! Get off!
烏拉？　　塞普蒂默斯
-Una? -Septimus.
烏拉！　　姐姐！
-Una! -Sister!
特裡斯頓！別這樣！特裡斯頓！
Tristan! No! Tristan!
我是你的…我是你的…母親
I'm your... I'm your... I'm your mother.
我是你的母親
I'm your mother.
幹得好　　　她可以解脫了，是的
-Rather well. -Good riddance to you. Yes.
哦！
Oh!
讓我們把火滅了
Let's put out those flames.
好嗎？
Shall we?
那麼，現在怎麼辦？
So, what happens now?
我們得學會一起生活
We have to Iearn to live with each other.
永遠？
Forever?
我們繼續吧
Let's get on with it.
像個男人一樣，我知道你會的
Be the man that I know you are.
出去　　　好的
-Get outside. -Okay.
走
Go.
特裡斯頓！　　抓住他
-Tristan! -Get him.
走開！
Get off!
Get out!
那麼，想變成什麼？浪漫的年輕人？
So, what's it to be, Prince Charming? Frog or tadpole?
青蛙還是蝌蚪？
塞普蒂默斯？
Septimus?
特裡斯頓！
Tristan!
年輕
Youth.
美麗
Beauty.
對我都不再有意義了
It all seems meaningless now.
我的姐妹們死了
My sisters are dead!
我在乎的東西都離開了我，走吧
Everything I cared about gone.
你們走吧
Go.
走吧！
Go!
不！
No!
我得謝謝你了，孩子
I owe you thanks, boy.
她的心要是碎了…對我來說就毫無價值
What use was her heart to me when it was broken?
你除掉了我的姐妹，她的心就全歸我一個人了
And you got rid of my sisters and now I can have it all for myself.
抱緊我，閉上眼睛　　　什麼？為什麼？
-Hold me tight and close your eyes. -What? Why?
星星會什麼？
What do stars do?
照耀吧
Shine.
好啊！　　太棒了！
-Bravo! -Yeah!
非常好
Very good.
你為什麼不早點這麼做？
Why didn't you do that earlier?
沒有你我是做不到的
I couldn't have done that without you. No star can shine with a broken heart.
心碎的星星是不會發光的
我以為我會失去你
I thought I'd Iost you.
但你回來了
But you came back.
當然回來了，我愛你
Of course I did. I Iove you.
來吧
Come on.
特裡斯頓
Tristan.
風暴要塞血統，最後倖存的男性繼承人
The Iast surviving male heir of the Stormhold bloodline.
就是你，特裡斯頓
It's you, Tristan.
但如果他是風暴要塞的新國王，那…
But if he's the new King of Stormhold, then...
現在我為風暴要塞國王特裡斯頓加冕
I crown thee King Tristan of Stormhold.
好啊！
Yeah!
我送你的禮物
My gift to you.
給你們兩個的
To you both.
謝謝
Thank you.
他們統治了80年
They ruled for 80 years-
但沒人可以永生
But no man can live forever,
除非他擁有星星的心
except he who possesses the heart of a star-
亞伊尼把她的那顆心完全獻給了特裡斯頓
And Yvaine had given hers to Tristan completely-
當他們的子孫長大的時候
When their children and grandchildren were grown,
也就是點燃巴比倫蠟燭的時候
it was time to light the Babylon candle-
在那之後，他們仍然快樂地活著
And they still live happily ever after-
導演：馬修·沃恩
魔幻星塵
主演：克萊爾·丹尼斯
主演：查理·考克斯